Irving R. Kaufman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings, 1945-1991 (Box 131-143)
  - Articles
    - 1952, June, "Observations on Pre-Trial Examinations in Federal and State Courts"
    - 1955
      - July, "Report to Committee on Pre-Trial Procedure of the Judiciary Conference of the United States"
      - Fall, "John Marshall: A Dedication"
    - 1956
      - Jan., "Further Observations on Transfers Under Section 1404(a)"
      - Apr., "Sentencing and Correctional Treatment under the Law Institute's Model Penal Code"
      - May, "Suggestions for Judges in the Calendar Part"
      - Oct.-Dec., "Calendar Decongestion in the Southern District of New York"
    - 1957
      - Feb., "The Former Government Attorney and the Canons of Professional Ethics"
      - Nov., "Report on Study of the Protracted Case"
    - 1958
      - Apr., "Masters in the Federal Courts: Rule 53"
      - June, "The Defense of Unpopular Defendants"
      - Dec., "The Federal Rules: The Human Equation Through Pretrial"
    - 1959
      - Jan., "Use of Masters to Preside at the Taking of Depositions"
      - Feb., "Pre-Trial in Criminal Cases," 1958-1959
    - 1959-1960
      - Winter, "Have Administrative Agencies Kept Pace with Modern Court-Developed Techniques against Delay?"
    - 1960 (Box 132)
      - Jan., "Sentencing: A Judge's Problem," 1958-1972, (2 folders)
      - Mar., "Decongestion through Calendar Controls
      - Aug., "The Apalachin Case: Further Observations on Pre-Trial in Criminal Cases"
    - 1962, Apr., "The Grand Jury: Sword and Shield"
    - 1963
      - Dec., "The Supreme Court and Its Critics," 1963-1966
    - 1964
      - Jan., "The Trial Lawyer: The Legal Profession's Greatest Asset"
      - Sept., "The Criminal Justice Act and the Indigent Defendant: A Milestone on the Path to Even-handed Justice"
    - 1965, Jan.
      - "In Defense of the Advocate," 1964-1966
      - "The Uncertain Criminal Law: Rights, Wrongs, and Doubts," 1964-1969
    - 1966
      - Oct., "The Confession Debate Continues," 1965-1968, (2 folders)
      - Nov., "Courts in Crisis: Progress Versus Intransigence," 1966-1969 (Box 133)
    - 1967
      - Oct., "A Fair Jury: The Essence of Justice"
      - Nov., "Dilemma in Crime Reporting"
    - 1968
      - Oct., "Improving the Juror's Lot and His Opportunity for Service"
      - Dec., "The Courts and the Public: A Problem in Communication," 1968-1969
    - 1969
      - Summer, "Forward: Jury Selection in the Fifth Circuit"
      - Sept., "Judge's Talents Must Never Be for Sale"
      - Undated, "The Judges and Jurors and Recent Developments in Selection of Jurors and Fair Trial-Free Press," 1968-1969
    - 1970
      - Winter, "Lions or Jackals: The Function of a Code of Judicial Ethics"
      - Mar., "Order in the Courts: Two Views"
      - Apr., "Judicial Review of Agency Action: A Judge's Unburdening"
      - Sept., "The Obstreperous Defendant and the Rule of Law"
      - Oct., "The Medium, the Message and the First Amendment"
      - Nov.
        - "Court Crisis: A Matter of Volume and of Money," 1970-1972
        - "Judicial Crisis, Court Delay and the Para-Judge"
    - 1971, Nov.
      - "Power for the People and by the People: Utilities, the Environment and the Public Interest"
      - "Free Press-Free Trial Issue"
    - 1972
      - Jan., "The Jury System at an Unmarked Crossroad"
      - July, "Harbingers of Jury Reform"
      - Aug.-Sept., "Court Delay and the Wasted Jury"
      - Dec., "Prison Reform: The Dilemma of Our Judges"
    - 1973
      - Spring, "The Second Circuit Review"
      - Mar., "Prison: The Judge's Dilemma"
      - Oct., "Individual Responsibility Is Still Paramount"
    - 1974
      - Feb.
        - "The Court Needs a Friend in Court"
        - "When to Cross-appeal or Cross-petition: Certainty or Confusion?"
      - July, "Advocacy as Craft: Law School Is More Than a `Paper Chase'"
      - Oct., "The Pre-Argument Conference: An Appellate Procedural Reform"
      - Dec.
        - "The Judge and the Sentencing Disparity"
        - Untitled (re sentencing)
    - 1975
      - Winter
        - "Attacking Anomie in the Legal Profession"
        - "Second Circuit Note, 1973 Term, Forward: The Sentencing Process and Judicial Inscrutability"
      - Jan. "Musings about the Present Role of Judges" (Box 134)
      - Mar.
        - "Judges Should Explain Sentences Publicly"
        - "Making Punishment Fit Crime"
      - May, "Does the Judge Have a Right to Qualified Counsel?"
      - June, "A Free Speech for the Class of '75"
      - Nov.
        - "Can Sentencing Be Demystified?"
        - "The Lawyer's Ethical Dilemma," 1975-1976
      - Dec., "A Response to Objections to the Second Circuit's Proposed District Court Admission Rules"
    - 1976
      - June, "Of Juvenile Justice and Injustice"
      - July, "Press, Courts: No Need to Fight `Like Tigers'"
      - Nov., "Judicial Reform in the Next Century," 1976-1977
      - Dec., "The Injustices of Plea-Bargaining," 1976-1977
    - 1977
      - Feb., "The Second Circuit: Reputation for Excellence"
      - Mar., "Press Coverage of Court Rulings Falls Short"
      - Apr., "Appellate Advocacy in the Federal Courts"
      - May, "Justice Requires Faith in Individuals"
      - Nov.
        - "Helping the Public Understand and Accept Judicial Decisions"
        - "Protecting the Rights of Minors: On Juvenile Autonomy and the Limits of Law," 1977-1978
    - 1978
      - Jan., "Litigants in Search of Able Advocacy"
      - Feb., "The Fifth Anglo-American Exchange: Some Observations," 1977-1978
      - May, "Let's Not Forget the Good Things Amid Fashionable Attacks on the Bar"
      - June, "Some Hard Questions for Law Graduates"
      - Aug., "After One Century in the Vanguard, the Bar Cannot Rest on Its Laurels"
    - 1979
      - Jan., "Keeping the Press, and the Judiciary, Independent"
      - Mar., "Chilling Judicial Independence"
      - Oct.
        - "Juvenile Justice: A Plea for Reform"
        - "Prisons: A Public Responsibility"
    - 1980
      - Mar., "Psst! Locker-room Gossip Now Sits on the Bench"
      - Apr., "Maintaining Judicial Independence: A Mandate to Judges"
      - May, "The Essence of Judicial Independence"
      - Oct., "Criminal Procedure in England and the United States: Comparisons in Initiating Prosecutions"
      - Nov., "A Legal Remedy for International Torture"
    - 1981
      - Jan., "Charting a Judicial Pedigree"
      - Mar., "See the Founding Fathers Stir"
      - Apr., "Assaults on Courts Endanger Union" (Box 135)
      - Apr., "An Open Letter to President Reagan on Judge Picking"
      - Aug., "Challenge to the Courts: The Coming Constitutional Crisis"
      - Sept., "Congress v. The Court"
      - Nov.
        - "Prison Reform: A View from the Bench"
        - "Looking Back Over Thirty-Two Years: Some Thoughts"
    - 1982
      - Jan.
        - "Judges Must Speak Out"
        - "When a Judge's Silence Is Not Golden"
      - June, "The Cost of Justice"
      - Aug., "The Insanity Plea on Trial," 1982-1983
      - Nov., "The Media and the Juries"
      - Undated, "The Child in Trouble: The Long and Difficult Road to Reforming the Crazy-quilt Juvenile Justice System"
    - 1983
      - Feb., "Public Is Legally Ignorant, Needs Some Education"
      - Mar., "Attorney Incompetence: A Plea for Reform"
      - June, "Reassessing the Fairness Doctrine"
      - Aug., "Utopia without Lawyers"
      - Dec., "Church, State Tangles"
    - 1984
      - Apr., "The Verdict on Juries"
      - June, "The Judicial System, Ailing, Needs Help"
      - July, "Press, Privacy and Malice: Reflections on New York v. Sullivan"
      - Oct., "The Anatomy of Decision Making"
      - Dec.
        - "Eulogy for William S. Landon"
        - "Keeping Politics out of the Court"
    - 1985
      - Mar., "To Keep Lawyers from Going Wrong"
      - June, "Streamlining the Federal Courts"
      - June-July, "Do the Costs of the En Banc Proceeding Outweigh Its Advantages?"
      - Aug.
        - "Congress Should Preempt Libel Field, Set Remedies"
        - "The Future of Libel Litigation: A Suggestion for
          - Reform"
      - Oct., "Life-and-Death Decisions"
    - 1986
      - Feb., "What Did the Founding Fathers Intend?"
      - Mar.
        - "A Dedication to Joseph R. Crowley"
        - "Must Every Appeal Run the Gamut?— The Civil Appeals Management Plan"
      - May, "Justice Unfunded Is Justice Undone"
      - Aug., "Cold-Blooded Killers, Not Freedom Fighters"
      - Oct., "The Battle Over Drug Testing"
      - Undated, "The Second Circuit Review"
    - 1987
      - Jan., "No Way to Interpret the Constitution"
      - Apr., "The Creative Process and Libel"
      - July, "North's Bicentennial Lesson"
      - Oct., "The Public's Right to Speedier Justice"
      - Undated
        - "The Original Intent Debate: A Judge's View on Interpreting the Constitution"
        - "Spinning the Seamless Web of Constitutional Interpretation"
    - 1988
      - Jan., "Congress as Court: The Role of the Judiciary in Protecting Witnesses' Rights," 1987-1988
      - Mar., "Electoral Integrity vs. Free Speech (Box 136)
      - July, "Awaiting an Answer on Courts as Censors"
      - Aug., "What Lawyers Owe to Justice"
      - Nov.
        - "Crowded Courtrooms: Jury's Still Out on Judges-for-Hire"
        - "New Remedies for the Next Century of Judicial Reform: Time as the Greatest Innovator," 1988-1989
    - 1989
      - Jan., "Not Ready for Prime Time in U.S. Courts"
      - June, "The Ruling on Rose: Out of Left Field"
      - Nov., "Reflections on 40 years on the Bench"
    - 1990
      - May, "Speedy Justice—At What Cost?"
      - July, "Nibble at Freedom and Risk Losing It All"
      - Oct.
        - "Idealism vs. Reality"
        - "Reform for a System in Crisis: Alternative Dispute
          - Resolution in the Federal Courts," 1990-1991
    - 1991
      - May, "Squandering Future Talent"
      - Sept., "Would Roe's Demise Sink Privacy?"
    - Undated
      - "An Appeal for Public Service"
      - "Broken Contracts"
      - "Children in Trouble"
      - "The Constitution: Does the Framers' Intent Cast Light or Darkness?"
      - "Courtroom Heroes and Anti-Heroes"
      - "Irving R. Kaufman: Reflections on Selected Topics"
      - "Justice and the Individual"
      - "Lesson in History: Does Baseball Need a New Umpire?"
      - "Press Coverage and the Courts"
      - "Reforming the Juvenile Justice System"
      - "Rico Redux: Cleansing the Waterfront"
      - "Thurgood Marshall: A Tribute from a Former Colleague"
      - "Tribute to Chief Justice Burger"
      - "When Will We Stop Playing Games with Our Children?"
  - Book reviews, 1973-1977
  - Letters to the editor, Mar. 1968-Nov. 1989
  - Research material
    - 1945-1986, (3 folders)
    - Undated (Box 137)
  - Speeches
    - Nov. 1947-Nov. 1961, (6 folders)
    - Apr. 1962-Aug. 1969, (6 folders) (Box 138)
    - Mar.-Sept. 1970, (3 folders) (Box 139)
    - 16 July 1971, (2 folders)
    - 16 July 1971, (1 folder) (Box 140)
    - Sept. 1971-Apr. 1974, (6 folders)
    - May 1974-Sept. 1977, (7 folders) (Box 141)
    - Jan. 1978-Mar. 1982, (7 folders) (Box 142)
    - Sept. 1982-June 1991, undated, (8 folders) (Box 143)
- Formerly Restricted, 1976-1978 (Box 144)
  Case files of Buckley v. Littell and Turpin v. Mailet.
  Arranged and described according to the series and container from which they were removed.
  - United States Court of Appeals, Second Circuit (Box 144)
    - Court Papers
      - Case files (Container 30)
        - Sept. term 1975, Buckley v. Littell, 1976-1977
        - Sept. term 1977, Turpin v. Mailet, 1977-1978
- Scrapbooks (Oversize), 1951-1970 (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  News clippings.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Vol. 1, Mar.-May 1951 (Box OV 1)
  - Vol. 2, Dec. 1952-Apr. 1956, undated (Box OV 2)
  - Vol. 3, Feb. 1956-June 1970 (Box OV 3)